MD SAIF SIDDIQUE RAYHAN

Software Engineer

West Rampura, Dhaka
(+880) 1676-449264
✓ saif.rafi07@gmail.com

saifsiddiquerayhan https://github.com/saifsiddiquee https://stackoverflow.com/users/10585447

CAREER OBJECTIVE

4 years experience in mobile application development using native and cross platform technologies. To pursue a challenging career and be part of a progressive organization that provides scopes to enhance my academic knowledge along with professional experience and to reach the pinnacle in the computing and research field with sheer determination, dedication.

WORK EXPERIENCE

DECEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

BRAC IT Services Ltd. - Software Engineer

Android | Flutter | Java | Kotlin | Dart | Jetpack

- Worked with the business team to prioritize the list of enhancements and new features for our Smart Microfinance android application.
- Worked with the UI designer to implement the new UI design with best practices for mobile devices.
- Integrated backend API service along with other services.
- Dynamic UI generation from json or backend API.
- Rapidately worked with data sync management.
- Integrated the offline database (Room/Sqlite) and experienced writing complex queries.
- Worked with the room database migration.
- Unit-testing code for robustness, including edge cases, usability, and general reliability.
- Rapidly fixing bugs and solving problems.
- Consistent pairing with and mentoring junior engineers on the team.

FEBRUARY 2019 - OCTOBER 2020

Royalty Bangladesh Inc. - Android Developer

Android | Java | Jetpack

- Designed and implemented the UI with best practices for all types of mobile devices.
- Integrated backend API service along with other services.
- Integrated payment gateway services.
- Interacted with other engineers to learn and spread best practices.
- Worked with documenting the existing code base.
- Maintained published applications and continuously integrated new features.
- Integrated analytics and crashlytics to identify the bugs and unexpected behaviors.

OCTOBER 2018 - JANUARY 2019

Geeks'n'Technology Ltd. – Programmer Intern

Android | Java | PHP | Laravel

- Interacted with other engineers to learn and spread best practices.
- Learned business logic and coding structure from the existing code base.
- Implemented the assigned feature and learned to debug.
- Worked with web technologies
- Learned and practiced the android architecture and lifecycle components.

PROJECT ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Smart PO

BRAC microfinance Android application for Programme Organizer (PO)

- MVVM architecture.
- Device Registration with unique device Id.
- Fully offline capabilities with sync.
- Long running background task management with workmanager.
- Complex and optimized database queries.
- Dynamic UI generation form json.
- Notifications
- Remote config

Playstore:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.bracits.smartpo

Smart BM

BRAC microfinance Android application for Branch Manager (BM)

- MVVM architecture.
- Device Registration with unique device Id.
- Combination of Online and Offline with manual and auto sync mechanism.
- Long running background task management with workmanager.
- Notifications
- Remote config

Playstore:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.bracits.smartbm

Royal Touch

A-share market Flutter application for retail stock brokerage Google Play Store:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.royalcapitalbd.apps.royalcapital

Apple App Store:

https://apps.apple.com/us/app/royal-touch/id1612836493?fbclid=IwAR0S5GimGD6VjmLsBfGZWd0LNFNVN007CXvkUzDs1NwyhisZBSoecWjejml

Royalty - Discover offers, discounts & rewards

A loyalty platform Android application with payment gateway https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.royalty.bd

Royalty Merchant

Merchant Android application for registered merchants

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.royaltybd.royaltybd_merchant

Royalty Sales Force

Sales Android application for sales team of Royalty

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.royaltybd.royalty_salesforce

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Excellent communication skills in both technical and non-technical discussions.
- Strong Java and Kotlin programming experience working in Android development.
- Proven experience consuming RESTful JSON APIs.
- Experienced in working with android dependency injection Dagger2.0 and Hilt.
- Practical knowledge of common data structures and software design practices.
- Experienced in cross-platform application development using Flutter.

INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES

- Latest technologies
- Jetpack Compose
- Photography
- Competitive Gaming
- Problem solving

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

SEPTEMBER 2019 - APRIL 2021

Jahangirnagar University - M.Sc in CSE

CGPA: 3.75/4.00

JANUARY 2015 - DECEMBER 2018

American InternationalUniversity - Bangladesh - B.Sc in CSE

CGPA: 3.47/4.00

PUBLICATION

Controlling Multimedia Player With Eye Gaze Using Webcam.

This application detects the eye gaze of a user sitting in front of a webcam. By tracking the eye it can control multimedia player functionalities such as play, pause, fast forward, and back forward.

https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8644103

ONLINE PORTFOLIO:

https://saifsiddiquee.github.io/